Alright, in the last class, we've already added the backend for this VD.
We've also added the model files for this VD.
And we've set up the environment as well.
Now, in this class, we'll dive into implementing the code.
First, let's create this just like we did before.
In the AI repository,
create a VD directory.
Then, we'll create two files in this directory.
Just like this one, okay?
There are two files in here, right?
We do it the same way.
One is the base.
The other one is the SLR.
In this base file,
we
will write our code.
First, we need to create a class.
And this is VD.
This is ABC
Can you add it?
This is the same as before, right?
What we create here is the same, right?
All these names need to meet this requirement
Then we will create them uniformly here
Like creating instances
Oops, I just put this in here
I made a mistake
It's not here.
This is essentially creating an abstract method.
To check if it's muted.
The input is the instance of your connection.
Then, the audio is passed in.
Specifically, the user's audio is passed in.
And it ultimately returns whether it's muted.
Here, we'll specifically implement it.
Of course, before implementation,
Let's start by writing the configuration.
In this configuration,
we'll first write the configuration in this template.
First, we'll write a VD here,
capital VAD,
then we'll write the SLR here,
and then,
we'll write the TDVD configuration here.
for this type.
This name
needs to match the file name
make sure it aligns with the file name here
and also, the directory for our model
the model directory is under the module directory
under this directory
let's change this
to VD
and then
And then, the smallest one
We copy this over
The shortest silent time in milliseconds
That is, if it remains silent for 600 milliseconds
It is considered to be in a silent state
Then we need to set a threshold value.
A threshold, basically
If it exceeds this threshold, it’s considered to have sound
If it’s below this threshold, it’s considered noise
There might be some noise or silence.
After this configuration is done,
let's write our class.
How should we write this class?
First, let's initialize it.
We'll copy it over.
Add it in.
Let's write this part.
Alright, let's take a look.
How is this initialization done?
The first step is to load the model.
We use this method to load the model.
It's loaded using the PYTORCH method.
It's loaded.
First, we need to specify the directory.
The model directory is in the configuration file.
The CONFIG passed in is from this episode.
This episode has already reached this level.
Then we'll make a copy of this and place it here.
Because we'll be using this one in the end.
Let's copy and place it here.
Like this.
Then we can continue looking.
In this spot.
We're loading the local model on our end.
To load the local model.
Then let's take a look at this.
We don't need to reload this one.
Then, the model file is named this way.
This name will be taken from this directory.
That is, from our model directory.
It will look for a file with the same name in there.
And it's loaded in the doge style.
It loads this JIP format.
Then let's see the model it returns after loading.
After loading.
It will return two items.
One is the model itself.
That is, a mod of the model.
The other is a utility class.
We only need the model itself.
The utility class is not required.
So we won't take it.
Here, it's crucial to select the zeroth element of the array.
The very first item in the list.
After obtaining it
then this is the registration log
it's essentially importing the log
and here we are creating the OPEDS encoder
the decoder, that is
because we ultimately need to decode the incoming audio as well
the incoming audio is in OPEX format
so we add an OPEC decoder
and this channel is a single channel
And 16K Hz
This should be consistent with what we had before, right?
This is where we get the threshold value for the configuration
Which is 0.5 by default, as we just set
And this is where we get the
Duration of the operation
The default is 800
But we configured it to be 600, right?
And here is where we parse it when needed
Use a buffer to receive this uh
Place the decoded PCM data into this buffer
Let's take a look at how to parse it in a moment
Then, let's define a few variables here
Let's look at these two variables
So, how do we proceed?
Let's copy this over first
Let me check it out
First, we'll start here
Through this decoder
we decode the OPEX data we input
since it's 60 milliseconds per frame, right?
This is minus six
After obtaining the PCM data
we place it in this buffer
put it in the buffer
after that
We process 512 sample points each time
which means multiplying by two
that’s the number of bytes, right?
each sample point is two bytes, right?
so two bytes, correct?
then we define a variable here, which is
whether there is any voice
set it to false initially
meaning no voice, right?
Then, let's move on to this part.
The while loop continuously parses the array in this buffer.
It parses the array inside.
Now, let's take a look.
Regarding this part,
if its length, the BP length, is greater than what we need to parse,
we start parsing it.
We keep parsing it continuously.
Let's review this section here.
First, let's grab this one quickly.
We've covered this step before.
Here, we start from zero and take the numbers from 1 to 10.
Right, 2 and 4.
Actually, it takes 1023.
1024 won't be included.
This is what we get after fetching all these blocks.
These are the blocks we need to work with.
Then, we'll remove this block from the buffer.
It's about reducing and removing force, right?
We've talked about this before.
So, moving on.
Here, we convert the PCM binary digits
the cash flow
data into tensor data.
Let's see how we can implement this later.
Let's move forward for now.
Because when we do inference, we use PyTorch.
When making inferences,
he uses Zhang Liang's data.
And here,
we prohibit gradient computation during inference.
If you don't understand this,
you can think of it as
we simplify the inference process.
This means that during the process, there would be many gradient outputs,
as well as recording these intermediate values.
Store intermediate values
We won't let it store here
This makes the inference faster
Because our main goal is to identify it
Whether there's any audio
Then we start the inference at this step
This is the inference
We loaded the model just now
And then we pass in the tensor data
That is, the tensor data of our audio.
Then, for the 16K frequency band.
And then,
Here, the conversion is to a threshold value.
Converting it to a threshold value.
Here, it's converted into the flow format.
Then, we evaluate this threshold value.
This threshold value is greater than the one we set in the Settings.
greater than or equal to our threshold setting
This means there's audio.
This is what we're working with.
Then we start the evaluation here.
If the previous one...
If the current one...
If the current one is silent.
It's a node, right?
False, correct?
We set it to false here.
Then, if it's currently muted,
and the last time there was audio,
this is similar to what we implemented on the hardware side,
it works the same way here.
First, we need to ensure it has audio before determining if it's muted, right?
It wouldn't make sense to check for muting at the very beginning.
So, we need to confirm that it is currently,
in a muted state,
while the last time there was audio.
So we'll calculate the current silent period.
Let's import this first.
This is how we calculate the duration.
What's the issue?
Subtract the current timestamp in milliseconds from
the last time there was speech.
The time when there was activity.
We'll record that in the next step, right?
This is the duration of the silence.
This duration exceeds our settings.
This minimum silence duration.
So the 600ms we set, right?
If it's longer than 600ms,
we consider it as silence.
It means the sentence has ended.
So we set this to true.
It indicates it has stopped.
Then we set this to false.
We'll wait for the next one.
Then it returns TRU here.
That means we've completed this sentence.
Otherwise, in this case,
If not,
If it is true,
it indicates there is currently audio.
If there is audio,
Let's set this to true
Then, record the time when there is audio.
This is ultimately used here, right?
So, this records the last time there was audio.
Here, subtract the current time from
the last time there was audio.
Wouldn’t that be the time it was silent?
Then, this part returns false.
Meaning there is audio.
So, it returns false.
No voice response, return true
This is the entire implementation process
Then, for the tensor conversion here
Let's write a piece of code
Let's copy this part over
Where should we put it?
We'll put it in this base
We'll implement it here
Because this is a more general approach
We might need to use this here.
So we'll use it here.
Let's add it.
Let's see how it converts.
It starts off like this.
Our PCM data is a
binary byte stream.
Although it's in an array format,
it's actually a byte stream.
We need to convert it into an NP array.
An Intel 16 array.
Our P4M data is in Intel 16 format, right?
Because it has both positive and negative values, right?
It's two bytes.
So it's of the Intel 16 type.
We will use this method for the blue screen issue.
Then we pass the byte stream data of our P4M into it.
And the type conversion is to NP's int16.
This becomes an array of PCM int16 after the conversion.
This is an array of NIN.
Then we convert this int array
into a float32 array.
We use the same method for this.
Here we pass in float32.
After this conversion,
the data will have decimal points.
This one doesn't have decimal points.
It's an integer, right?
But this one we have with a decimal point.
And it's 32-bit.
Then, we need to perform normalization here.
This normalization,
is actually for when we do the inference,
as it requires normalized data.
Because it only needs probability data, you see.
Probabilities ranging from 0 to 1 or -1 to 1, right?
This is like a percentage, right?
It's normalized.
So we normalize it here.
We take the entire dataset and
divide it by 32768.0.
This data represents the range of our int values,
which is the positive and negative range.
If you consider it as such, you can calculate it.
For example, if it's 32768
It's essentially the largest data value.
It's one, yeah.
If it's negative,
32768 is the smallest data value.
It's one, indeed.
It divides by one.
Ultimately, the data here,
is a value between -1 and 1.
It's structured like this.
Then, here we use the touch method to
convert this normalized data into tensor data.
The final step is to return this to the upper layer.
Then it will use this tensor data for inference.
This is how it's implemented.
Let's take a look now.
This is where the logic lies.
It's not that complicated overall.
We mainly focus on its activity detection,
voice activity, to be precise.
The core inference happens here.
That's the extent of the inference.
We can understand this part simply for now.
We'll go into more detail later.
Regarding the inference here,
it uses the tensor data input to the model,
the main point is how this tensor data is transformed, right?
After the transformation, the inference follows,
and the output is quite straightforward.
The output is a neatly organized result for us,
whether it meets a certain threshold or not,
it's about whether it meets the criteria or not,
it's a threshold value,
it's a probability value,
regarding this probability value,
we compare it with the set threshold,
to determine if it's silent or not silent, right?
That's all for this lesson.